adjustable kettlebells serve a solid
purchase for anyone with a home gym not
only are they going to save you money
compared to buying a full set of
traditional kettlebells but they're also
going to save you a ton of space there's
a lot of options out there to choose
from one of the most popular ones is the
Bowflex select Tech 840 adjustable
kettlebell it's going to replace six
individual kettlebells it's super easy
for you to adjust the weight and it's
also one of the easiest ones for you to
get your hands on we got a lot to talk
about today so let's go ahead and get
right to it
[Music]
thank you
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and this time
around we've got the Bowflex selectec
840 adjustable kettlebell
in the garage for review now if you
don't know how this video is going to
work today I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about this
kettlebell we're going to talk about the
price we're going to talk about the
features we're gonna go over some of my
pros and cons but most importantly we're
going to talk about who should or maybe
should not add this to their home gym
setup now before I start talking my head
off and doing all that I gotta let you
know we've reviewed a ton of kettlebells
on barbin.com and we also made a best
list if you want to check out our top
picks all you gotta do is search barbin
best kettlebells it'll pull right up for
you you can go over everything
okay so Bowflex has a lot going on with
the 840 that I like and I want to talk
about that for just a second and first
of all I think we have to talk about the
amount of floor space you're going to be
saving that's because this kettlebell
replaces six individual kettlebells
weight ranging from 8 to 40 pounds
that's honestly a really solid number
for the majority of beginner athletes
maybe some intermediate ones as well and
also if you're just new to kettlebell
training this can be a pretty solid
weight range for you it's really easy
for you to adjust the weight just simply
twist this knob right here I could do
this this whole video it's honestly kind
of fun and it sounds good A little ASMR
going on here today at bar Bend but
honestly that's that's just a really
nice thing makes it super quick and easy
you know in between sets if you're
working out with a partner you know
they've need heavier or lighter weight
than you that's going to be a really
nice thing for you it's honestly pretty
comfortable on your wrist and on your
forearm right here which is a really
nice thing because there's so many
kettlebell workouts that require it you
know to be in that racked position and
you know sitting there on you it's also
pretty competitively priced at around
150 bucks and you can purchase it you
know through the Bowflex website on
Amazon or even just at your local
sporting goods store so you know that's
just another really solid thing going
for it in my opinion
foreign
[Music]
so let's talk about a few potential cons
you may experience with the Bowflex 840
and first of all we got to talk about
the available weight so yeah I just got
done saying you know eight to 40 pounds
it's pretty solid for you know a good
amount of people but there's also a you
know a good amount of people that 40
pounds is not going to be enough and you
know there's even some exercises with
myself that I need more than 40 pounds
so definitely keep that in mind you know
this might not be the best option you
know basically because of that also you
know the handle right here is pretty
slick in my opinion and it's also welded
to the top of the Kettlebell right here
and it's pretty thin so definitely keep
that in mind there's a ton of plastic
used right here now the actual here I'll
go ahead and pick this up right here and
as you can see these plates these are
steel plates but you know on the outside
that is plastic and then everything else
right here is plastic everything the
little mechanism on the inside now these
walls are pretty thick so I don't really
think that durability is going to be you
know too much of an issue but it also
says you know on the top right here do
not drop and that's because it's plastic
so you know if you're working on you
know working out on like rubber flooring
that might be okay but definitely you
know you don't want to be dropping this
bad boy too much especially if you're
working out on side on concrete or
anything and you know it's kind of hard
to do you know there's a lot of
kettlebell workouts where you know you
kind of drop it or just you're setting
on the ground you know pretty violently
I guess you could say so durability
could be you know a pretty big issue for
some people so you definitely want to
keep that in mind as well
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money now
and once again the Bowflex select Tech
840 is listed for right around 150 bucks
plus shipping is free and I think we all
enjoy free stuff now compared to the
rest of the market you know this is a
pretty fair price yeah there's some that
are cheaper I don't know you know about
the quality of those this is actually
pretty
pretty quality product considering there
is a good amount of plastic involved
right here now there's also some that
are going to be way more expensive but
those are going to be you know cast iron
or you know basically fully full metal
build for the most part at least now
when comparing you know this purchase to
traditional kettlebells this is going to
save you a whole lot of money you know
obviously with a full set but even with
the 8 to 40 pound range which once again
you know that's what you're getting
right here so if you are you know
wanting a compact option that works
across all your lifts and you know saves
you money this is a really good option
for you to consider
[Music]
yeah
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with the
Bowflex 840 and I want to go top down so
starting with this handle it's
definitely under 30 millimeters in
diameter now I don't know the exact
diameter but it's pretty thin now it's
also pretty slick in your hands and it's
welded to the top of the Kettlebell
right here which you know for that to
actually you know come into effect
durability issues and that weld to you
know deteriorate on you it's going to
take a really long time a lot of heavy
usage but you know that's not ideal for
everybody out there so you know
definitely keep that in mind so right
here though this is the only metal you
know that is involved everything else is
plastic including this adjustment
mechanism which honestly is really easy
for you to do
simply twist it it's going to go from 8
to 40 pounds in just a matter of seconds
and I actually like how it's 360 and
there's actually you know two options
for every single weight that makes sense
so you got eight pounds right here if
you keep going you know and then you got
your 40 right here and then it goes
right back to age and that's kind of a
nice touch now let's go ahead and lift
this bad boy up as you can see you know
fully plastic right here even this
actual stem you know whatever you want
to call it that mechanism now it does
kind of wobble it's a little loose right
here and I don't know if that's going to
be you know detrimental in the long run
with the actual product itself but it's
definitely something that I notice so
keep that in mind now once again you
don't want to drop this right it's
plastic you run the risk of it breaking
it even says on the top Do not drop but
this is pretty thick so you know if
there is the occasional accidental drop
and I don't think it's going to break
the first time that that happens I do
like how there is some rubber right here
four little pieces of rubber
to be nice as you go to set it down it's
going to protect your flooring which is
cool now these plates on the inside
they're steel but it's plastic on the
outside and so
there's just a whole lot of plastic you
know I I'm not too crazy about that
that's probably you know gonna wear down
and obviously you're gonna have to use
it a whole lot for that to really take
place and take effect but you definitely
run that risk more so than compared to
you know a kettlebell that only you know
uses steel for example but overall this
is a really nice design it's super
Compact and I like how everything just
kind of stacks right here and you have a
little cradle right here definitely here
let me go ahead and put this on 40 and
pull this out
so you got your little stand cradle
whatever you want to call it right here
this is also plastic so whenever you go
and house it definitely want to be
careful because you don't want to break
that either
[Music]
all right so I want to go ahead and give
you guys the full demo with the Bowflex
840 and I'm going to reiterate you know
a lot of things I just talked about a
second ago but I want to show you up
close all right so let's talk about the
handle first
once again this is under 30 millimeters
in diameter so it's it's pretty narrow
and it's also pretty slick now it could
probably come in handy you know whenever
you put it in that front rack position
you're kind of rotating it in your hands
but overall
it's you know not my cup of tea I guess
you could say because it kind of makes
me feel like my hands are sweaty even
when they're not so definitely keep that
in mind also you know it's welded to the
top of the Kettlebell right here and
it's typically not what you're looking
for with a kettlebell because it kind of
runs the risk of you know accelerated
wear and tear
I personally think it's going to take a
really long time but that's still
something you know worth you know having
at the Forefront of your mind also you
know this is the only steel that's
involved in this entire build other than
the weighted plates I'll talk about
those in just a second but yeah
everything else is in fact plastic
including
the outer shell right here so you
definitely don't want to drop it it says
on the top of the adjustment mechanism
Do not drop definitely you know don't do
that occasionally might be fine but
don't do that a lot now once again it's
super easy for you to adjust the weight
you kind of got a rubbery you know
texture right here on this dial you just
twist it and twist it and twist it and
twist it and twist it it's honestly kind
of fun to do now go ahead and pull this
out as you can see all your weight
plates are you know stacked nicely right
here and they're not the same weight
okay so this weighs eight pounds on its
own then you know this is four pounds
because you jump to 12 pounds total then
you're jumping to 20 25 35 40 so you
know it's all it's all varying right
there in weight and you know these are
in fact Steel on the inside but they're
you know coated in plastic so
you know it over time you know
especially with you know the the stem I
guess I guess what you want to call it
in here that is probably going to wear
down but it's still my only that still
might take you 10 years or so so you're
going to get you know a lot of usage out
of this kettlebell now
let's talk about this stem it kind of
wobbles a little bit right here and I'm
not like you know using a whole lot of
effort I don't know if that's really
gonna you know negatively impact you in
the long run just something worth
mentioning and I know I just said you
know don't drop it you definitely
shouldn't but this is pretty thick this
plastic is pretty thick right here so
you do have that occasional drop it's
going to happen from time to time you
know it's it's kind of the inevitable
with the Kettlebell I think it's going
to hold up I don't really want to go
outside especially on on concrete I
don't really want to just sit here and
test that and and break my new toy but
you know it's definitely you know I
think it can handle at least some
beating and then you know you have some
rubber right here on the bottom that's
really nice I like that it's actually
built into the actual the shell of the
Kettlebell rather than being on the
bottom plate there's some out there that
you know only have that rubber coating
on that bottom plate you're not always
using that so it's really nice how you
know that's always going to protect your
flooring which is really cool and then
you just set it down right here on the
top and then you're good to go now
whenever you have it on 40 pounds and
you want to you know say you move it
outside for a nice outdoor workout
whenever you pull this out you are going
to have to make a separate trip you know
just to get your you know your cradle
right here and this is
pretty you know fragile this is pretty
some pretty fragile plastic so whenever
you do have 40 pounds really I guess
anytime just be careful and don't slam
it down because you definitely run the
risk of cracking that and you just
certainly do not want that to happen
[Music]
all right
okay so let's take a second and talk
about you know who should or maybe
should not purchase this kettlebell and
I want to talk about the people who
should first now you know if you live in
an apartment and you know you don't have
all the space in the world for a bunch
of equipment or maybe just you know your
home gym is kind of small or maybe
you're just wanting you know a
kettlebell to take on a trip with you
this is a really solid option you know
it's really compact
it's going to replace six individual
kettlebells weight up to 40 pounds I
mean this is this is a pretty pretty
solid option for a lot of people and
also it's relatively affordable you know
it's about 150 bucks that is because
there is a lot of plastic involved right
here but for somebody who doesn't want
to spend you know more than 150 bucks
more than 200 bucks you know whatever
this is you know really really solid for
you now let's transition to you know who
shouldn't purchase this and we got to
talk about the weight range first
I said earlier you know 40 pounds is a
pretty solid weight range you know
specifically for you know beginners to
you know some intermediate lifters but
if you need more than 40 pounds then
well you're gonna have to go elsewhere
you cannot expand on this Bowflex does
not have you know a heavier adjustable
kettlebell so definitely keep that in
mind and then also you know it's the
plastic you know plastic is you know not
ideal for everybody you know if you're
somebody who you know is probably going
to be a little bit rough with your
kettlebells now this really just isn't
going to be the product for you
foreign
that's all I got for y'all today on the
Bowflex select Tech 840 adjustable
kettlebell I know I've been talking a
lot about you know how much plastic is
involved and the fact that this only
caps out at 40 pounds but I honestly
enjoy this product it's super easy for
you to adjust the weight it's going to
replace six individual kettlebells and
it's only 150 bucks which is a really
nice thing thanks for watching y'all I
hope this video was really helpful and
that I was able to answer every single
question you have about this kettlebell
as always keep your eyes peeled for my
next video but for now I want you to
head over to barbin so we have a full
written article ready for you to go it's
going to pop up right here in the corner
but you can always just search bar Bend
Bowflex select Tech 840 adjustable
kettlebell review it's going to pull
right up for you I'll catch y'all next
time
[Music]
all right